Guide to the James R. Bettinger papers SC1317
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
James R. Bettinger papers
1989-2016
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Bettinger, James.
SC1317
15 Linear Feet (10 boxes)
Conditions Governing Access
Selection Records (Boxes 9 & 10) are restricted for 75 years from date of creation. The materials are otherwise open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.The materials are open for research use.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Jim Bettinger, 2016.
Scope and Contents
Papers include Bettinger’s files from the John S. Knight Journalism Fellowships; the Bill Lane Center for the American West; the Stanford Daily; the Trotter Group; as well as miscellaneous files and proofs.
Biographical / Historical
James R. Bettinger graduated with honors from University of California at Santa Barbara in 1969, and worked as a journalist for over 20 years. He served as director of the John S. Knight Journalism Fellowships from 2000-2016.
Journalism -- United States.; Journalism -- Study and teaching.; Bettinger, James.; Bettinger, James.; Bettinger, James.; Bettinger, James.; Stanford University. John S. Knight Journalism Fellowships; Bettinger, James.; Stanford University. John S. Knight Journalism Fellowships
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2017-160
  - ASNE, 1993-2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ASNE/APME, 2014 Sep (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Bill Lane Center for the American West: Advisory Council, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Bill Lane Center for the American West: Direct Democracy, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Bill Lane Center for the American West: On The Edge, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Bill Lane Center for the American West: Sustainable Forestry, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Communication Department, 1991-2009 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Computers: unlabeled, 1990-1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Computers: Power Book G3, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Computers: unlabeled, 1991-1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Computers:MacSamson, 1995 Sep (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Computers: LELAND/UNIX, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - GSB 496, 1990 Winter (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Journalism Program Review: Review 2009 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Journalism Program Review: Review 2005 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - JSK 1 of 4: JSK Advance Information Packet, 1989-1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - JSK 1 of 4: Advance Info, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - JSK 1 of 4: JSK Advertising Conferences, 2003-2014 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - JSK 1 of 4: JSK Advertising - Events, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - JSK 1 of 4: JSK Advertising - Recruitment, 1989-2007 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - JSK 1 of 4: JSK Alumni Survey, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - JSK 1 of 4: JSK Alumni Workshop, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - JSK 2 of 4: JSK Asilomar 2000 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - JSK 2 of 4: JSK Application Brochure, 1997-2002 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - JSK 2 of 4: JSK Branding, 2009-2012 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - JSK 2 of 4: Christmas Brunch, 2000-dec (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - JSK 2 of 4: JSK Catering, 1990-2001 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - JSK 2 of 4: JSK Child Care, 1991-2005 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - JSK 2 of 4: Disabled Fellows, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - JSK 3 of 4: Fellowship Programs - Other, 1990-1999 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - JSK 3 of 4: JSK Financial, 2000-2004 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - JSK 3 of 4: JSK Housing - On campus, 1990-2000 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - JSK 3 of 4: JSK Housing - Off campus, 1990-1999 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - JSK 3 of 4: JSK Innovation Workshop 2016 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - JSK 3 of 4: JSK - Lokey, 2004-2008 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - JSK 4 of 4: JSK Long Range Projects, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - JSK 4 of 4: JSK Newsletter, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - JSK 4 of 4: JSK Newsletter - Examples, 1987-1999 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - JSK 4 of 4: JSK Office, 1996-2001 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - JSK 4 of 4: JSK Orientation, 1996-2000 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - JSK Misc., 1991-2006 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - JSK: PWR Presentation, 2009 Aug 10 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - JSK: JSK Program Committee, 1983-1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - JSK: JSK Re-engineering Journalism 2014, 2011-2014 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - JSK: JSK Re-engineering Journalism 2011, 2011-2012 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - JSK: Scotland Memorial Fellowship, 1991-1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - JSK: Sponsored Accounts, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - JSK: JSK Website / Project Posts, 2012-2013 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - JSK Fellows by name: Imtiaz Ali, 2006-2008 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - JSK Fellows by name: Quian Kejin, 2013-2014 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - JSK Fellows by name: Yung-te Lee, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - JSK Fellows by name: Wanja_Njuguna, 2003-2005 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - JSK Fellows by name: Martin Quiroga, 2013-2014 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - JSK Fellows by name: Danyel Smith, 2013-2014 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - JSK Fellows by year: Advisees 2012 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - JSK Fellows by year: John S. Knight Fellowships booklets, 2011-2012 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - JSK Fellows by year: 2009-2010 Projects (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - JSK Fellows by year: Class of 2015 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - JSK Fellows by year: Class of 2013-2014 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - JSK Fellows by year: Class of 2009 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - JSK Fellows by year: Class of 1992 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - JSK Fellows by year: Class of 1991 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - JSK Knight News, 2000-2008 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - JSK Reunion: JSK Reunion 2013 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - JSK Reunion: Reunion 2009 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - JSK Reunion: JSK Reuinion 2005 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - JSK Reunion: JSK Reunion 1993 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - JSK Senior Fellow: Overholser-Senior Fellow 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - JSK Senior Fellow: Russell Baker text Jan. 1999, 1999 Jan (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - JSK Senior Fellow: Senior Fellow 1 of 3, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - JSK Senior Fellow: Senior Fellow 2 of 3, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - JSK Senior Fellow: Senior Fellow 3 of 3, 1993-1997 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - JSK Senior Fellow: Senior Fellow 1998 - 1999 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - JSK Senior Fellow: Senior Fellow 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - JSK Senior Fellow: Tony Lewis, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - JSK Sonoma Trip, 1990-2008 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - JSK Tax Information - For Fellows, 1990-2008 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - JSK TruthBooks Course Evaluations, 2009-2015 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - KF Innovation Lab, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Knight Lecture: Knight Lecture 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Knight Lecture: Knight Lecture 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - KZSU, 1997-2011 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - KZSU, 1999-2011 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - IAPA Board of Directors, 2008-2009 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - KZSU: KZSU 2000-01, 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - KZSU: KZSU 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - KZSU: KZSU 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Master's Theses, 1992-2005 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneuos: Miscellaneous, 2000-2003 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous: unlabeled, 1985-2000 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Misc. Articles, 2009-2010 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1987-2011 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Misc.: unindexed, 1992-2011 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Misc.: unindexed (1), 2008-2013 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Misc.: unindexed (2), 1997-2015 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - NABJ, 1989-1992 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - NAHJ, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - NAJA, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - newspapers - chair national 1995-2004 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - newspapers - chair national 1989 - 1994 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - ONA 2009 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - ONA 2014 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - ONA/Stanford Partnership, 2007-2008 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Recommendations, 2006-2008 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Reliable Resource, 2014 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Remodel 2012-2013 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Federal Credit Union, 2005-2010 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Daily 1 of 2: Stanford Daily Board Minutes, 1990-1996 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Daily 1 of 2: Stanford Daily Bylaws org., 1990-1993 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Daily 1 of 2: Stanford Daily Editor-in-Chief, 1994-1996 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Daily 1 of 2: Stanford Daily Financial, 1989-1995 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Stanford Daily 2 of 2: Stanford Daily Foundation, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Stanford Daily 2 of 2: Stanford Daily Lease (1 of 2), 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Stanford Daily 2 of 2: Stanford Daily Lease (2 of 2), 1972-1994 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Stanford Daily 2 of 2: Stanford Daily Task Force, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Stanford Daily 2 of 2: Stanford Daily World Cup (1 of 2), 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Stanford Daily 2 of 2: Stanford Daily World Cup (2 of 2), 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Teaching, 1989-1991 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Transcending Borders: Pacific Salmon Conference, 2005-2007 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Trotter group: Trotter columns, 1994 Nov (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Trotter group: Trotter - Food Lodging, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Trotter group: Trotter group, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Trotter group: Trotter Mtg. 2006 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Trotter group: Trotter Mtg. 1998 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Trotter group: Trotter Ogletree RDTBL, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Unity 1999 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Uncorrected Proofs (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Uncorrected Proofs (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Selection Records (Restricted for 75 years)
    - Selection - US, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 2010 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - 2009 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - 2008 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - 2007 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - 2006 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - 2005 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - 2004 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - 2003 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - 2002 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - 2001 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - 2000 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - 1999 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - 1998 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - 1997 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - 1996 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Class of 1994 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - 1993 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - 1992 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - 1991 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - 1990 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - 1989 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - 1984 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Selection - US, 2017 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Selection - JXITL, 2017 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - 2016 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Class 2014-2015 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Selection - INTL, 2016 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Selection - INTL, 2015 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Selection - US, 2015 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - 2015 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Selection - INTL, 2014 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Selection - US, 2014 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - 2014 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Selection - US, 2013 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Selection - INTL, 2013 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Selection, 2013 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - 2013 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Selection - INTL, 2012 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Selection - US, 2012 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - 2012 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Selection - US, 2011 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Class of 2011 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - 2011 (Box 10, Folder 28)